<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Martí Comas</title>
	<link>http://localhost:1313/tags/social-media/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Social Media on Martí Comas</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 10:46:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	
	
	<item>
		<title>I hate the modern web</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/i_hate_the_modern_web/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 10:46:08 +0200</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://localhost:1313/i_hate_the_modern_web/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/stupid.jpg#cover&#34; alt=&#34;stupid&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;start&#34;&gt;Start&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been realizing how the internet has become a big monopoly, people
don&amp;rsquo;t navigate across different websites to find cool stuff but rather go to the
same few sites (YouTube, Facebook, Twitter, Reddit&amp;hellip;) and consume the internet
through their lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-good-side&#34;&gt;The good side&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am aware that that has some advantages and it seems a reasonable place we&amp;rsquo;d
end up given enough time, it removes the effort of having to find those sites
in the first place, for videos there is YouTube, for friends posts there&amp;rsquo;s
Instagram, for discussions on topics there is Reddit&amp;hellip; It also works the other
way around, if you want your content to be seen it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to do so on
a platform that already has people on it instead of creating your own, that can
help small businesses make themselves known, it has created &amp;ldquo;content creator&amp;rdquo;
careers where with people that live of of that now and I&amp;rsquo;m sure anyone could
come up with more positive points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-not-so-good-side&#34;&gt;The not-so-good side&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as always this comes with some bad, most of the internet has shifted to be
&amp;ldquo;algorithm friendly&amp;rdquo; and whose sole purpose is to get views which later become
monetized. The problem are the algorithms, every modern website has some sort
of system to determine what to show you next, first notice the word &amp;ldquo;show you&amp;rdquo;,
you are not searching for something, but rather consuming what&amp;rsquo;s being fed
through your screen, even on cases like YouTube where you have to click on a
video to watch it you clicked on it because it was shown to you, people rarely
watch a video that wasn&amp;rsquo;t shown either on the Home or the Recommended section,
and that&amp;rsquo;s the best case scenario, things like TikTok, Instagram, Twitter you
just mindlessly scroll over hundreds of posts that a robot is serving to you,
worst thing is most of the time you can&amp;rsquo;t even recall a fraction of what you saw
once you are done with it, does that happen with anything else &lt;strong&gt;you enjoy&lt;/strong&gt; in
your life? Have you ever watched a movie, played a game, went out with some
friends, and not been able to recall 90% of it? Mind the emphasis on &amp;ldquo;you enjoy&amp;rdquo;,
if its a boring movie you might not pay attention and not recall, if you are
in school on a subject you don&amp;rsquo;t like you won&amp;rsquo;t remember as much&amp;hellip; But, you
like watching social media, do you? At first people&amp;rsquo;d agree, that&amp;rsquo;s why they
consume it all the time, but does that not contradict with every other activity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thats-only-social-media-right&#34;&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s only social media, right?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the web works on the same fashion now, news sites always have clickbait
titles to get you in, and once you enter, you get bombarded with recommended
articles. Even cooking tutorial sites like cooking ones try to trap you as
much as they can with nonsense stories and filling hiding the true content for
which you are in the site to begin with, online shops, app stores, and basically
everything follows the same &amp;ldquo;feeding you content&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;trapping you in&amp;rdquo; rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-do-they-want-to-keep-you-in&#34;&gt;Why do they want to keep you in?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ads, ads and ads (and selling your data, tracking you across devices, making a
profile from all you do online&amp;hellip;) and more ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &lt;em&gt;So are you against companies making money online? Do you want everything for free?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, first there are multiple ways for companies to make money online that don&amp;rsquo;t
include tracking you and selling your data. Also, in real life ads don&amp;rsquo;t target
you specifically, the ads on a country might not be the same as in another, but
it still is a general ad, its not been served to you after studying the best way
to influence you specifically by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/12/no-a-marketing-firm-isnt-tapping-your-device-to-hear-private-conversations/&#34;&gt;listening&lt;/a&gt; -
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.com/just-how-much-does-your-phone-listen-to-sell-you-target-1848495516&#34;&gt;through&lt;/a&gt; -
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dobetter.esade.edu/en/phone-listening-personalized-ads&#34;&gt;your&lt;/a&gt; -
&lt;a href=&#34;https://futurism.com/the-byte/facebook-partner-phones-listening-microphone&#34;&gt;microphone&lt;/a&gt;
and many more sketchy tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;companies-want-to-own-you&#34;&gt;Companies want to own you.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The businesses model has shifted, online companies providing you with a
service you need and you giving them money in exchange does not ocurr on the
big platforms people use (yes, there are online courses you pay for, some paid
news letters, and those are great! Unless they also use any of the scummy
tactics mentioned previously), but rather, they try to monopolize a format
(like YouTube with videos, and Instagram with Posts) and then play with your
brain to keep you in, althoug it may seem radical, they are literally feeding
from your attention, they keep you in a trance-like state for hours at a time
and rewrite your brain into comming back for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/evil-attention-farming.png#cover&#34; alt=&#34;farming&#34; title=&#34;Hello&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image is just a meme, but if someone who had no idea about the internet read
all this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t they imagine something somewhat similar?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;moving-forward&#34;&gt;Moving forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already taken some steps away from all of this, although ofcourse I can
only act for myself, I deleted Instagram long long ago, I never had a TikTok,
I stopped using reddit in 2023 and in June 2024 I finally quit Twitter, my
last splinter is YouTube and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I won&amp;rsquo;t stop using completeley, but
I still took some action, from now on I&amp;rsquo;ll use YouTube without an account to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminate any sort of algorithm based on my history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not have a subscriptions system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be refreshing to see if there are new videos, I&amp;rsquo;ll instead use
a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/M4rti21/dotfiles/blob/main/scripts/book&#34;&gt;bookmarking script&lt;/a&gt;
I made to save the links to the channels I might want to see from time to time.
Also I&amp;rsquo;ll use an &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/enhancer-for-youtube/&#34;&gt;extension&lt;/a&gt;
to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Force theater mode so I don&amp;rsquo;t get distractions while watching a video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll still have the recommendations at the end of a video, and I don&amp;rsquo;t fully see
it as a bad thing, because I don&amp;rsquo;t have an account recommendations will only be
based off of this one video I&amp;rsquo;ve just watched so it&amp;rsquo;ll be a good way to find new
content I might like but it won&amp;rsquo;t be enough for it to create a profile on me and
feed me random content, is it just as bad? You could argue it is, I might change
this page in the future if my stands on this change, but for the time being,
this is it :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PD: No way anyone reads this ever but whatever ¯\&lt;em&gt;(ツ)&lt;/em&gt;/¯&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been heavily inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz&#34;&gt;Luke Smith&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@MentalOutlaw&#34;&gt;Mental Outlaw&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@EricMurphyxyz&#34;&gt;Eric Murphy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
